Agents are powerful, but they're
unreliable and overconfident. They rush
to start coding and waste time building
the wrong thing. They claim success when
they're clearly not done. They
hallucinate APIs and libraries, and when
they add one feature, they break three
others. Using agents means endless
reviewing and frustrating attempts to
correct mistakes after the fact. Tesla
solves this with specd-driven
development, keeping AI agents on rails
and well informed. It gives you the ease
of agent decoding with the quality of
production software. The Tesla framework
integrates with your agent and makes it
define the product features in a spec
before writing the code. Each spec
contains tests that verify the code
meets the requirements, so the agent can
keep iterating until it gets it right.
Specs don't need to slow you down. You
can choose to review them before
building the code to ensure your intent
was well captured, or you can vibe spec
and let the agent flow from spec to
code, only checking the specs if
something goes wrong. Either way, the
specs become part of your codebase and
serve as long-term memory of what your
product should do. Agents can evolve the
product better this way, and tests
ensure that they don't break what's
already working.
Tesla's spec registry helps agents use
open source software better. It includes
over 10,000 usage specs for popular
libraries, preventing API hallucinations
and version confusion. Usage specs are
packaged and versioned just like
software modules, and you can publish
your own custom context to the registry.
Together, the framework and registry
ensure your agents know what and how you
want them to build. Specdriven
development is the way to build software
in the AI era. It makes agents better
with little extra effort and unlocks
their use in professional code bases.
The Tesla framework and registry are now
available in beta. Try them out. I can't
wait to see what you build.